

Morerio Paolo
Via Grigna 11
20052 Monza-Milan
H.P. +39039320867
M.P. +393357595947
paolo.morerio@invensys.com
morerio.perucchetti@inwind.it

Please find attached my C.V.

I give consent to the use of my personal details according to the Italian law 675/96.

Conscious that, the experiences acquired in twenty years of professional carrier give me the opportunity to fill a manager role, I would like to take the chance to underline the fact that I have always worked in multinational companies, whose main sectors have dealt with "Instrumentation and control". My main tasks have dealt with instrumentation for industrial control within the Oil & Gas, Power Production, Olefin and Fine chemicals sectors and other industrial branches; hence my well developed knowledge of production sectors, within various professional roles.

As far as my current **Senior Client Sales Executive** role is concerned, I think it not only identifiable with sales activities but it also one of the most important and sensitive figures, whose task is to understand the changes and the needs of the market. My training background allows me to have a highly technical trade perspective, thanks to the Product Manager, Project Manager and Project Leader roles I have held. As my job within the company plays a very important role, I have always given great importance to personal training.

I thank you in advance for your attention and look forward to hearing from you at your earnest convenience.

Your Faithfully.



June 2010 CURRICULUM VITAE

Morerio Paolo
Via Grigna 11
20052 Monza-Milan
H.P. +39039320867
M.P. +393357595947
paolo.morerio@invensys.com
morerio.perucchetti@inwind.it

### **Professional experiences**

### January 2005/up to now, Invensys Systems Italia spa: Senior Client Sales Executive

Invensys Systems Italia, Italian branch of Invensys Operation Management is a multinational company operating in the "Instrumentation and control" sector with a 70 million USD turn-over.

I'm working in the European Sales Organization, Major Project Group with my Line Manager, GM of MPG. I have the responsibility of the major Italian EPCs like Saipem, Foster Wheeler, Tecnimont, Techint, Siirtec Nigi. I'm managing the whole Invensys portfolio: DCS, ESD, F&G, OTS, APC, M&I and sub suppliers are the principal items. I'm in strictly relationship with the worldwide sales organization to have the right coordination for the international opportunities covering the end user side. I'm in touch with the national and international proposal department defining the best solution for the project; during the project execution I'm constantly updated by Project Manager.

The targets finalized for Invensys Systems Italia from 2005 are the following:

- Budget FY 05/06 3.5 MUSD → value reached 3.6 MUSD
- Budget FY 06/07 8.5 MUSD → value reached 14.6 MUSD
- Budget FY 07/08 6.5 MUSD → value reached 18.4 MUSD
- Budget FY 08/09 10 MUSD → value reached 19.6 MUSD

# The main deals won are the following:

- Saipem Onshore: CTE ERG Nuce Nord, Horizon Oil Sand, Superocatos Plant Venezuela, Aramco OTS
- Tecnimont: QCHEM QC2 SIS, KPPC Aromatics, TASNEE Petr.Company, KPPC PyGas
- Foster Wheeler: Bapco Desulphuration, IES MN Refinery
- Saipem Offshore: FPSO Gimboa
- Techint: EMethanex Methanol plant
- Maire Tecnimont: Colbun Coal Fire Power Station, Endesa Coal Fire Power Station

## 1998 - 2004, Yokogawa Italia srl: Area and Key Account Manager

Yokogawa Italy is a Japanese multinational company operating in the "Instrumentation and control" sector with a 17 million Euro turn-over.

I worked in the Sales Sector with my Line Manager and my area was composed of Piemonte, Liguria, Toscana, Marche, Sardinia and Milan area with direct and indirect sales agents.

These agents promote the "field instrumentation" (such as pressure transmitters, flow transmitters, temperature transmitters, level transmitters, pH analytical measures), supervision and control systems (single loop controls, PLC, DCS, ESD, F&G, BMS). I personally dealt with the main customers, developed the company's strategies and the automation control and safety systems.

On the basis of the different production and trade realities, together with the marketing sector, I decided what kind of strategies we should develop to face each situation.

I had also the responsibility of the mayor Italian EPC like Snamprogetti, Saipem, Tecnimont, Techint, Foster Wheeler.

In May 1998 I was given an area worth 1,5 million Euro. Within 18 months I have taken on many direct agents: thanks to a new trade strategy and to an agreement with an Italian builder I have been able to double our turn-over.

The last value of my turn-over was 5 million Euro.

### 1991 - 1998 Elsag Bailey Hartmann & Braun

#### January 1997- April 1998, Elsag Bailey Hartmann & Braun spa: Sales Account Manager.

This company, belongs to the Italian-American multinational group Elsag Bailey Process Automation, was ranked second in the automation and instrumentation sector, being the first Italian company in this sector. It was set up through the Elsag Bailey and Hartmann & Braun Italia merger. In 1997 it had a 200 billion turnover

In this company I held the position of Sales Account Manager and Area Manager.

The former, directly coordinated by the Sales Line Manager, dealt with the development of the automation sector (DCS-PLC).

I took part in the trade decisions of the Board of Directors, providing them with important technical/economical information and I collaborated with Project Managers and Project Leaders.

The latter dealt with systems integrators and with the development of trade strategies concerning Freelance 2000 (ex Digimatik). Such strategies mirrored a new trade network (Service structure, Training structure, online support), which I personally developed.

## 1991 - 1996 Hartmann & Braun Italia

#### January 1994/December 1996: Product Manager

As Product Manager I represented the Italian branch in the general Task Force of developing market strategies and automation systems. I taught my colleagues the main aspects of technical/economical structures and I supported all the Italian sales sector as far as the "mini DCS" was concerned. Hence my role as link between the German parent company and the Italian branch.

In 1994/95/96 we succeeded in having the best results on an international level, by increasing the turn-over by 50%.

In January 1996 I was given the opportunity to become Manager of the integrated system sector. This was a new market for Hartmann & Braun, who continued to develop in this area in the 1997 merger with Elsag Bailey.

# July 1991 – December 1993: Project Leader Project Manager

My career began as technician and I had, among other projects:

- Project Leader in "Desox" system for P.S. in Brindisi Sud.
- Project Leader in "Denox" system for P.S. in Rossano Calabro.
- Control systems of "Desox" for P.S in Fiumesanto
- Control systems of "Denox" for P.S. in Fiumesanto.
- Fume control systems for P.S. in Fiumesanto.
- Control systems for P.S. in Pietrafitta Nuova.

Thanks to such projects I have developed my technical and managerial competence.

#### **Education**

July 90 University Degree in "Electronics Automation Engineering", Politecnico in Milan.

Result:83/100. Thesis: "New results in the study of matrix-tactile-sensors"- reporter

Prof. M. Somalvico

September 91 specialization "Vapour generator checking"

July 92 specialization course Goldamnn-Cegos Associati "Product Orientation"

October 92 specialization course Goldmann-Cegos Associati "The product Manager and communication"

June 94 specialization course Goldmann-Cegos Associati "Sales strategies"

January 06 sales value

#### Personal details

I was born in Monza (close to Milan), 02/03/1964 I am married and I have one son My level of English is Upper Intermediate

Company Position: sCSE

Company Benefits: company car, mobile phone, note book, sanitary assurance.

Gross Annual salary: 108.000,00 EURO, included MBO (from 50% of Annual Salary)

MBO achieved on FY  $06/07 \rightarrow 25.000,00$  Euro MBO achieved on FY  $07/08 \rightarrow 105.000,00$  Euro MBO achieved on FY  $08/09 \rightarrow 88.000,00$  euro

Main